

Email <u>manish shah@me.com</u>

Mobile +64 27 535 7874

Portfolio http://designbymanish.com

Social Linkedin Instagram Facebook

Design & me

Clear thinking, strategic approach & e2e solutions. Few things that make my everyday exciting.

As a design expert, I've had 9+ years of industry experience, working on a broad spectrum of projects, ranging from products to services, across various touchpoints and platforms.

I strive to design innovative, intuitive & optimised experiences for effective & enjoyable use, from conceptualisation to research/testing to implementation.

Being always curious about new technologies, design processes & strategies helps me stay aware of the endless possibilities on my playground while getting a constant dose of inspiration.

Education

Master's In Strategic Design

Politechnico di Milano - Italy Sep-Dec, 2008

Scholarship offered by the Italian Institute of foreign trade — DIMI, at Politecnico di Milano, Italy.

Master's In Design, Visual Communication

IDC, IIT Bombay - India 2006 - 2008

BFA, Applied Arts

Abhinav Kala Mahavidyalaya, Pune - India 2001 - 2006

Vocational Course, Photography

Fergusson College, Pune - India 2005 - 2006

Strengths

Product strategy
Innovation
User Experience
Us

Problem-solving Conducting tests User surveys Managing / Mentoring Documentation
Coding - HTML, CSS
App development - Swift

Visual design

Experience



Watercare Services Limited

Senior UX Strategist – Contract May 2021 - Present



PlaceMakers

Lead UX Designer Feb 2020 - Apr 2021 (1.3 years) In my recent role as UX Design Lead at Placemakers, my goal is to build an in-house design team to improve the experiences and create a vision for future digital products. Additionally, I'm also aiming to influence design thinking maturity within the organisation. I have been responsible for delivering an e2e customer-driven product experience across an app and web portal that met the trade customer needs achieving higher adoption, sales and usage for the digital channels.



Datacom

Lead UX Strategist – Contract Oct 2019 - Feb 2020 (4 months) As a UX Lead, I was responsible for creating and validating Datacom's new information architecture for their website. The overall customer goal was to make the content accessible and logical to discover. Catering, both familiar & unfamiliar type of customers, our ultimate aim was to achieve two business goals "New acquisition" and "Sustain & Grow". Followed by designing website templates defining the content hierarchy and structure.



Air New Zealand

Senior UX Strategist – Contract Jul 2019 - Oct 2019 (3 months) As a UX Strategist, I'm responsible for influencing product teams to create and deliver user-centric roadmaps. The primary phase of my role is to help conceptualise, define, and design the future experience strategy for the customer journey, ensuring that we're delivering value to users & the business.



Qrious NZ

Lead UX Design – Contract Jun 2019 - Jul 2019 (2 weeks) I was leading a project with Qrious for one of their clients – Transpower, setting a product & experience design direction to build a consolidated & seamless experience for their systems, along with conducting stakeholder workshops for a collaborative outcome.



Spark NZ

Chapter Lead, UX Designer Nov 2015 - Jun 2019 (3.8 years) As the design chapter lead, I work collaboratively with key stakeholders & designers to align designs with the product vision, creating measurable experiences & solutions that meet business goals. Working within our user-centred framework, I support teams to challenge creative thinking & seek innovative

solutions to problems.

I also manage, mentor & supervise the design team on several project initiatives. Ensuring that all designs are executed at the highest quality, considering industry standards & customer needs.

One of my key projects was leading the design and the build of Spark's design system, Spark Experience Toolkit (SET), which included the formation of components and the digital style guide. I was also acting as a guardian for SET, ensuring the quality, reusability, consistency of the experiences.



Hewlett Packard Singapore Interaction Designer Jun 2011 - Oct 2015 (4.5 years)

My role at HP was to interpret business needs into effective design solutions, mainly for the printers.

I was responsible for redefining & aligning the UI direction for printer operating systems across different business segments - consumer, small business, & enterprise. These ranged across various touchscreen sizes, including both coloured & black & white interface.

As an Interaction Designer, I worked through the design process, starting from identifying user needs to conceptualising, creating design vision, workflows, interaction guidelines (UI architecture, patterns & behaviours) & UI prototypes. We regularly conducted the concept & usability testing to validate solutions.



Yahoo India

Visual & Interaction Designer Jan 2010 - Jun 2011 (1.6 years) My responsibilities included analysing online content browsing trends & anticipating/proposing future Yahoo products on various platforms, including mobile/tablets, web & software applications.

I worked closely with the business team for requirements to create concepts, wireframes, visual mockups.



Freelance

Design Consultant Feb 2009 - Nov 2009 (10 months) Working as a design consultant allowed me to work on multidisciplinary design projects (like interior designing, identity design & more), which included not just designing but execution, as well as management. It was a competitive experience altogether, which helped me acquire the potentials of an individual professional designer.